Finding Aid for the The Peter Taylor Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- Series V. Biographical/Personal Papers
  - Writings About Peter Taylor
    - Wager, Willis & Inez. Three short articles about Taylor, typescript, 1987[?] (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Wilson, Robert. Introduction for In The Miro Discrict, typescript, 1977[?] (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Unidentified. “Recollections of the Craigs,” typescript, 1985. (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Unidentified. “Peter Taylor: How a part-time student at Southwestern became the 1987 Pulitzer prize winner,” typescript. (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Genealogical
    - Data regarding Haynes, Baird, Taylor and Caswell families. (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Invitations
    - 13 Invitations. (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Photographs
    - 23 Photographs (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Business and Financial Records
    - Check register, 1980/81; List of expenses, n.d. Receipts, 1976, 1982 Land ownership and sale records, 1976, 1982. Mortage papers, 1982. Book orders, 1967, 1972. Postal receipts, 1965, 1967. Lists of letters (Elizabeth Hardwick and Robert Lowell) which were offered to Harvard, 1976. (Box 14, Folder 12)
- Series VI. Associates
  - Jarrell, Randall
    - Autograph, Articles contributed to Randall Jarrell, 1915-1965 by Robert Fitzgerald, Mary Jarrell, Bernetta Quinn, Robert Phelps, Peter Taylor (first page only), typescripts. Clippings and copies or reviews, articles and criticism by Sylvia Angus, Suzanne Ferguson, Harry Gilroy, Seymour Krim, C.E. Maguire, Delmore Schwartz, Parker Tyler, Erik Wensenberg, and Reed Whittemore. Typescript of poem “On Leaving The Clinic: For Randall Jarrell” by David Posner. (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Lowell, Robert
    - Announcement of memorial service, September 25, 1977. Review by Don Bogen. (Box 14, Folder 14)
- Series VII. Writings by Others
  - Identified
    - Babb, Howard Reprint “Setting and Theme in Far From The Madding Crowd.” (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Boeckman, Dan Untitled typescript (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Coffey, Shelby Untitled typescript (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Dew, Robb Forman Typescript, “A Satisfactory Life” (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Goodwin, Stephen Typescript, “The Man Who Melted” and “Evening Rain” (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Gwin, William Typescript, “In A Fair Fall, Smiling” (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Hamilton, Ian Typescript, “Robert Lowell: A Biography” (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Hannabury, James F. Typescript, “Isolation” (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Havird, David Typescript, “Habit of the Heart” (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Jarrell, Randall Carbon typescript, “The Lonely Man” [1963] (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Kelso, E.L. Typescript, “Stones In The Stream,” “Diamond Horse Shoe,” “Loch Ness Monster,” “Satan Complex” (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Lowell, Robert, Typescript and holograph “1974 (To Peter Taylor after his sickness)” “Afterlife (For Peter Taylor after his sickness)” The Afterlife (For Peter Taylor), two drafts “The Banker’s Daughter” “The Civil War Monument At Steubenville” “The Epigraph” (title “Verdancy” struck through) “Ford Madox Ford” “Hawthorne” “A Manichean Looks at the Civil War Monument at Steubenville” “The Maturing Time” (holograph draft, has football plays drawn on the reverse) “Of Man’s Last Disobedience” “Pro Patria Semper Sanguis” “To Peter Taylor on the Feast of the Epiphany” Untitled essay about Ford Madox Ford, two drafts (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - McAlexander, Hubert H. Reprint, “Flush Times in Holly Springs” (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - McLallen, Lyman, Typescript “Miz Sue’s Final Tragedy” “Legacies of the “Old South”” “One of the Big Shots In Town” “The Caddy” “Taps” “Sunday: Bellevue Baptist Church” “Salvation” “Adam & Eve” (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - O’Connor, Harrison, Typescript “Missionaries” “In The Bahamas” “Borrowed Away” “The Day We Ate Ber-stew” “Diary of Virginia Miller” Untitled (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Pinkham, Marjorie Stafford “Jean,” a 35 page typescript reminiscence of her sister, Jean Stafford. (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Quinn, Bernetta, Typescript “Thoughts after Hearing Songs For Eve in a Massachusetts Church” “Reverie in the Claremont Rose Garden” “The First Allens at Claremont” (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Ransom, John Crowe, Typescript “Master’s In The Garden Again” “Prelude to an Evening” (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Rhoden, Kerney, Typescript “Annunciation” “Platforms” “The Scenario” “Three Elements of Movement From Eisenstein” “Focus” “Primavera” “Archilochus And His Spear” (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Ross, Eleanor Notes; Contract for Welcome Eumenides; Poems for Welcome Eumenides, typescript. (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Shreve, Susan Richards Typescript, “Dear Beverly” (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Smith, Young Typescript, “The Stupid Bastards” (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Stafford, Jean, Typescript “Wu at the Democratic Convention” “My Mind to Me a Kingdom Is” (found with Stafford’s correspondence, but possibly by Robert Lowell, 1944) (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Stevens, Rodney Typescript, “Opponentless” (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Thompson, Jack, Typescript “Ending on Paumonok” Untitled “To Absent Friends” (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Warren, Robert Penn [?] Photocopy of untitled verse found together with letters from Warren (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - Wilkinson, Charles Typescript, “Fool’s Mate” (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - Williamson, Alan, Typescript “Paris, the Shortening Days” “Presence” (for Peter Taylor) “Heaven” “Good Dreams Are Shown In Nightmare Theaters” “Robert Lowell: A Reminiscence” (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - Winters, Anne, Typescript “Night Wash” “To New York” (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Unidentified
    - Unidentified, typescript of story, 12 p. (Box 15, Folder 24)
    - Unidentified, holograph story, 11 p. (Box 15, Folder 25)
    - Unidentified, “Prohibition,” “Unrhymed Hooey,” “No ’News” is good news,” Latin notes. (Box 15, Folder 26)
    - Unidentified, Typescript story, 17 p. (Box 15, Folder 27)
- “The Gift of the Prodigal.” Galleys, p. 1-20, with notes from New Yorker editors questioning words, suggesting alternatives, etc. Also questions from the Legal Department. [Removed from Series II. Writings]. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- A Summons To Memphis. Galleys dated April 11, 1986, p. 1-106, with editor’s notes and corrections. [Removed from Series II. Writings]. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- A Summons To Memphis. Galleys dated April 11, 1986, p. 1-106, with Taylor’s holograph corrections. Note on outside identifies as author copy, “Taylor – 1st pass”. [Removed from Series II. Writings]. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- A Summons To Memphis. Galleys, p. 1-110, with editor’s corrections. [Removed from Series II. Writings]. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- A Summons To Memphis. Galleys, p. 1-110, with Taylor’s corrections. Note on outside identifies as author copy, “Taylor – 2nd pass”. [Removed from Series II. Writings]. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- A Summons To Memphis. Galleys, p. 1-110, with Taylor’s holograph corrections. [Removed from Series II. Writings]. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Film Adaptations: “The Old Forest” Poster. [Removed from Series III. Literary Career]. (Box 1, Folder 7)